<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on synapse labs 🧠</title>
    <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on synapse labs 🧠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 09:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://synapselabs.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Master local presence and bring Home Assistant&#39;s areas to life with Magic Areas</title>
      <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/bring-home-assistant-area-to-life-with-magic-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://synapselabs.io/posts/bring-home-assistant-area-to-life-with-magic-areas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My biggest personal challenge in home automation is a quest to make everyday commoner tasks &amp;ndash; such as turning on and off lights, fans, air conditioners and media devices &amp;ndash; a thing of the past. My ultimate intent is to just do whatever I want to do and for &lt;del&gt;Skynet&lt;/del&gt; the house to figure it out what it is and act accordingly and when I&amp;rsquo;m done I can just walk away and things will turn off themselves. After a few years experimenting with all sorts of stuff, learning how to develop on Home Assistant, I finally came up with a custom component that replaced hundreds of lines of YAML and made me much closer to my goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating your Tesla with Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/integrating-your-tesla-with-home-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://synapselabs.io/posts/integrating-your-tesla-with-home-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a sweet electric car is sweet indeed. But integrating it with your home automation system, that&amp;rsquo;s even sweeter! Fortunately Home Assistant has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.home-assistant.io/integrations/tesla/&#34;&gt;native integration&lt;/a&gt; through Tesla&amp;rsquo;s cloud and with some Lovelace magic we can make the most out of it on our Dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a custom &#39;Residents&#39; card in your Home Assistant&#39;s dashboard</title>
      <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/lovelace-residents-card-for-home-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://synapselabs.io/posts/lovelace-residents-card-for-home-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shortly after I released &lt;a href=&#34;https://synapselabs.io/posts/battery-level-tricks-with-home-assistant/&#34;&gt;my latest post&lt;/a&gt;, a friend DM&amp;rsquo;ed me on Twitter and asked about my residents card that I showcased briefly, so it gave the perfect opportunity on making a post about it and share with the world this card that I enjoy so much. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy and it&amp;rsquo;s mostly vanilla Home Assistant/Lovelace so put your mad scientist lab coats, hop aboard and let&amp;rsquo;s learn how to make awesome display cards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battery level tricks with Home assistant</title>
      <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/battery-level-tricks-with-home-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://synapselabs.io/posts/battery-level-tricks-with-home-assistant/</guid>
      <description>There are several components in Home Assistant that report their battery level. Today we&amp;rsquo;re gonna learn how to do some cool tricks in order to get most of this information such as :
 Notifying Low battery sensors Grouping multiple battery sensors for the same device Getting your phone&amp;rsquo;s charging state by monitoring the battery level Reminder for charging your phone Tweaking the battery icon with charging states  Low battery sensors I have a bunch of wireless Zigbee and Z-Wave sensors integrated with Home Assistant. Even thou they&amp;rsquo;re very efficient by using deep sleep, I still have to change their battery from time to time and I&amp;rsquo;d rather be notified that I need to do so than one day realize something is not working because that sensor&amp;rsquo;s battery is dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a bed occupancy sensor with bathroom scales, ESP32, HX711 load-cell sensors and ESPHome on Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/bed-sensor-with-esphome-on-homeassistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://synapselabs.io/posts/bed-sensor-with-esphome-on-homeassistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After slapping around multiple &lt;a href=&#34;https://synapselabs.io/posts/multisensors-with-esphome-on-homeassistant/&#34;&gt;ESPHome-based multisensors&lt;/a&gt; around the house, I needed a way to keep them from going off while I&amp;rsquo;m sleeping and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite fond of manually disabling and re-enabling the automations in a daily basis. In order to get Home Assistant to know when myself or my wife are in bed, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to create custom bed occupancy sensors using a pair of bathroom scales, a pair of HX711 load-cell sensors on top of the same framework (ESPHome).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building custom multisensors with an ESP8266 and ESPHome on Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/multisensors-with-esphome-on-homeassistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 09:00:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://synapselabs.io/posts/multisensors-with-esphome-on-homeassistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like about the ESP family of micro-controllers is the amount of &lt;code&gt;3V3&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;GND&lt;/code&gt; pins on the board. That allows us to use only dupont cables and saves us from the hassle (or if you&amp;rsquo;re terrible at soldering &lt;del&gt;like me&lt;/del&gt;) of soldering stuff. This is an easy build, inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jpjfVc-9IrQ&amp;amp;t=640s&#34;&gt;BRUH Automation&amp;rsquo;s $15 Multisensor&lt;/a&gt; but using &lt;a href=&#34;https://esphome.io/&#34;&gt;ESPHome&lt;/a&gt; instead of custom code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Alexa to greet you with Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://synapselabs.io/posts/using-alexa-to-greet-you-with-home-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://synapselabs.io/posts/using-alexa-to-greet-you-with-home-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that makes everyone feels better despite having no friends, is having robots talking to you like they cared. From today on, every time you arrive home to your empty house &lt;del&gt;because your partner divorced you and took your kids and your dog&lt;/del&gt;, you will feel that warmth in your heart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
